Zach Weinberg

FULL-STACK WEB ENGINEER

Profile

Full-stack web developer with a focus on JavaScript and TypeScript. Loves learning new technologies and finding the right one for the job. Specializes in frontend libraries such as React with a Node.js backend, while also managing the entire deployment lifecycle.

Employment History

Full Stack Engineer, RedDoor, Remote

APRIL 2020 - PRESENT

- Currently helping to build the future of the mortgage and real estate industry by empowering home buyers to find the best mortgage for their needs
- Using React and Next.js for our completely custom mortgage origination web tools
- Managing Google Cloud deploys along with a GitHub Actions workflow
- Working on a TypeScript backend that uses Firebase for database functionality and real-time features to support our mobile apps
- Working closely with product teams to plan and execute on our goals
- Writing code to originate loans and guide customers through a great experience in our apps
- Maintaining refinance and purchase loan logic that is in production usage to help customers become homeowners

Full Stack Web Developer, Cubepros, Boston, MA

JANUARY 2019 - APRIL 2020

- Designed, built and deployed numerous full stack JavaScript applications (MERN stack), some of which are now available on the QuickBooks Online app store
- Built and maintained company web infrastructure from scratch, including their website and tools to help accountants optimize their workflows
- Core technologies included Node.js, React, Postgresql and SCSS
- Built a tool that connects Slack users with their QuickBooks Online accounting data via webhooks and user initiated commands
- Self-directed work much of the time
- Collaborated with designers to turn static designs into working websites
- Worked on Wordpress websites (PHP)

Web Developer, Tapfood, Madison, NJ

JUNE 2018 - JANUARY 2019

- Collaborated with CEO to design a RESTAPI that would support a food delivery service and implemented it using Node.js
- Built website frontend using React with a focus on simplicity and ease of use
- Migrated existing backend from Firebase to internal API with Postgresql
- Set up a bug alert pipeline, so bugs could easily be caught and fixed quickly
- Helped to achieve a consistent look and visual theme across the website by promoting design elements that are also prevalent in the tapfood iOS app
- Designed complex backend routes such as getting distances by GPS coordinates and search queries
- Built Twilio and Stripe integrations from scratch

Details

Boston, MA 508-314-2588 zweinberg3@gmail.com

Links

<u>zachweinberg.com</u>

GitHub: zachweinberg

Skills

Node.js

React

Git and GitHub

TypeScript

JavaScript (ES6+)

SQL

Next.js

Unit Testing

HTML & CSS

CI/CD

Vue

Google Cloud Platform

Heroku

Languages

English

Web Developer, My Bus Home, Boston, MA

JANUARY 2018 - JUNE 2018

- Contract position
- Created a Node.js website with Express and EJS that helps college students schedule bus transportation home during school breaks
- Built an admin panel for company employees to log in and manage trip reservations
- Built a bulk email sending queue with AWS SQS and Sendgrid

Freelancer, Upwork

DECEMBER 2017 - JANUARY 2020

- Helped clients from different backgrounds accomplish their web-related goals, most of which involved full-stack JavaScript
- Achieved "Top-Rated Freelancer" status on Upwork with a 99% job success score, which is still maintained today

Education

B.S. Economics, University of Massachusetts Amherst, Amherst, MA

SEPTEMBER 2013 - JUNE 2017

Although I did not study computer science in college, programming was still a passion of mine and I used it often (Python mostly) for economics-related work